<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andriy Utkin</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andriy Utkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 20:37:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to block Russia on your servers</title>
      <link>/2022/block-ru-nftables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 20:37:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/block-ru-nftables/</guid>
      <description>Hi dear reader!
It&amp;rsquo;s April 5, 2022, and it&amp;rsquo;s day 41 of a full-scale military invasion of Ukraine. The Armed Forces of Ukraine have just released Kyiv from semi-encirclement, liberated all of the Kyiv region as well as entire north of the country. The previously occupied towns and villages are scenes of thousands of disgusting war crimes committed by the russian beasts.
 Murdered on the spot civilians, some with tied hands, are lying on the streets in great numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to block Russia with OpenWRT</title>
      <link>/2022/block-ru-openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 13:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/block-ru-openwrt/</guid>
      <description>There are many potentially valid reasons you may want to be discriminate to countries on your personal computer or your network infrastructure.
 Distinct country-specific locality of your users or the resources you use. Distinct intensity of cyber attacks or threats. Legal restrictions (data protection laws, trade sanctions).  Particularly relevant, novel motivation as of March 2022 is the boycott of Russia in response to the invasion of Ukraine.
This is a purely technical article about how this can be achieved and what to expect as a result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Invasion of Ukraine</title>
      <link>/2022/russian-invasion-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 16:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/russian-invasion-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Hello, the Free World!
Not every software geek blog starts with a post about a war. A war which is bad enough to potentially become a world-ending nuclear world war. I am honored by this.
Ukraine, my fatherland, is under an unprovoked and aggressive full-scale military invasion from Russia and its satellite Belarus. You should know this by now, dear reader. But Ukraine fights. Fights with passion. Fights in yet-unseen unity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About me    I am a professional software developer.
Since the start of my career, I chose to work with systems based on Free and Open Source Software. I have never regretted this choice. The freedoms to use, learn, change and share the code always were important in helping me meet the ever changing needs of myself and others - friends, customers and employers. I am deeply thankful to those who made it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/merit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/merit/</guid>
      <description>Merit     Talk is cheap. Show me the code.
 Linus Torvalds
I have contributed to many public FOSS projects and made some myself. I was Gentoo Linux developer from 2017 until 2022. I operate an XMPP server since 2015.
Contributions to FOSS      Gentoo Linux:
 Developer 2017 - 2022. Brought in and mentored another developer. Contributor since 2015.    Linux kernel:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
