<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>humor on Andriy Utkin</title>
    <link>/tags/humor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in humor on Andriy Utkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:21:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/humor/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Committed to losing</title>
      <link>/2024/committed-to-losing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:21:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/committed-to-losing/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re the good guys. We are always ready to sacrifice ourselves for all the good stuff we love in the world.&#xA;But we never get to enjoy our life!&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s all their fault. They&amp;rsquo;re the bad guys - authoritarian countries committing genocides and other atrocities, companies harming the society and planet with their sick unsustainable practices, and simply criminals.&#xA;They tell us to tie our own hands or they&amp;rsquo;ll kill our beloveds whom they hold hostages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vile Way Nursery</title>
      <link>/2024/vile-way-nursery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:14:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/vile-way-nursery/</guid>
      <description>Take your child to the award-winning Vile Way Nursery, it&amp;rsquo;s the best you can do for them. And you want only the best for them, don&amp;rsquo;t you?&#xA;All educational materials used are our intellectual property. Sharing or studying without the prior written permission of CEO is strictly prohibited. This includes fairy tales, nursery rhymes, coloring sheets, games, toys and the layout and the likeness of the nursery estates. For the avoidance of doubt, at-home singing of the nursery rhymes your child learnt in the nursery is not permitted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customer Optics Manager</title>
      <link>/2024/customer-optics-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 11:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2024/customer-optics-manager/</guid>
      <description>Job title: Customer Optics Manager&#xA;Are you looking to make a galaxy-scale impact to the shareholder value?&#xA;Do you like to help real people (to keep living with the pain we cause them)?&#xA;We are looking for an A-Team player to add to our new Customer Optics division! (The old one has just been laid off.)&#xA;At AInitech, we are a family - we will encourage you to grow dependent on us for all your needs, but in return, you have to obey and know your place even if you disagree.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
